-=TLF字幕组=- 荣誉出品
翻译：诗 琪
君临
King's Landing
翻译：Hello_Agnes
翻译：LordVader
翻译：lydia萌
卡林湾
Moat Cailin
校对：LordVader
统筹：饭离烨
临冬城
WinterFell
特效：离太阳只有七步
绝境长城
The Wall
布拉佛斯
Braavos
弥林
Meereen
根据乔治·R·R·马丁著《冰与火之歌》改编
权力的游戏
第四季   第九集
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
电视剧编剧
戴维·贝尼奥夫 & D·B·威斯
导演
尼尔·马歇尔
长城上的守夜人
What was she like?
她长的什么样
She...
她…
she had red hair.
她长着红头发
Oh?
哦？
- How big were her feet? - What do you want me to say?
- 她脚多大？
- 你到底想让我说什么？
I want you to tell me what it was like to have someone.
我想让你跟我讲讲，拥有一个人是什么滋味
To be with someone.
和一个人在一起
To love someone and have them love you back.
爱着一个人，被人爱着是什么滋味
We're all gonna die a lot sooner than I'd planned.
我们的死期比我预想的要早得多
You're the closest I'll ever get to knowing.
你是我认识的人里面最亲近的一个
So you and Gilly never?
你跟吉莉没有？
No.
没有
She just had a baby.
她刚生孩子
And she never offered.
她从没提出过
But if she had,
但如果她提出
you would have?
你会吗？
You'd have broken your vows?
打破誓言？
The interesting thing is,
有趣的是
our vows never specifically forbid
誓言没有禁止…
intimate relations with women.
跟女人保持亲密的关系
What?
什么？
"I shall take no wife,"
“我将不娶妻”
yes, that's in there. There's no denying that.
没错，这句话是在誓言里头，毫无疑问
"I shall father no children." It's very specific.
“不生子”，这个也很明确
But what do our vows have to say about other...
但是我们的誓言里也没提到不能做其他的活动
activities is open to interpretation.
那是有待商榷的
I don't think Ser Alliser cares much for interpretation.
我觉得艾里沙爵士才不会管那么多
Anyway, there's nothing for him to interpret.
无论如何，没什么好商榷的
We didn't.
我们没干啥
So what's it like?
到底是什么感觉？
It's...
是…
there's this person, this whole other person.
有这样一个人，一个完完整整的人
And you're wrapped up in them and they're wrapped up in you.
她裹着你，你裹着她
And you--
而你…
for a little--
有那么…
for a little while, you're more than just you.
有那么一会儿，你不再是一个人…
You're-- I don't know. I'm not a bleeding poet.
你就…我不知道，我又不是个该死的诗人
No, you're really not.
是啊，你确实不是
What did I get for it?
我又得到什么了？
An arrow six inches from my heart.
一箭穿膛，离心脏就6英寸
There'll be arrows for all of us soon, I imagine.
我估计，我们很快都免不了中箭
There will.
是啊
They've already done the worst thing to me they could ever do.
他们对我已经坏事做尽了
Go get some sleep, Sam.
去睡觉吧，山姆
I'll take this watch.
这轮我放哨
Did I ever tell you about her?
我跟你说过她吗？
- My Sheila? - Yes.
- 我的小姑娘？
- 说过
That was a night to remember.
记得那是在一个晚上
Of course, I'd had a good bit to drink.
我的确是喝了点儿酒
Her fangs were sharp,
她那尖牙真是锋利
but she knew how to use them.
但是她也不会来
And she was nice and soft down below.
她下面那么美好，柔软
No, she was no ordinary beast.
她可真是非同寻常的野兽
Many is the man who--
曼尼是个…
I know you never fucked a bear.
我知道你没干过熊
You know you never fucked a bear.
你自己心里也清楚
Right now I don't want to think about the bear you never fucked.
现在，我不要想你那只没跟你搞过的熊
Right now all I want to think about
现在，我只要全心全意地思考
is each one of these arrows finding its way into a crow's heart.
怎么把这些箭射进乌鸦的心脏
We could be waiting here a while.
我们得在这儿等上一阵子
Good.
很好
The longer we wait, the more arrows I'll have.
等的时间越长，我就能做越多的箭
They came up here to our land
他们来到我们的土地上
and put up a big wall and said it was theirs.
建了一堵大墙，就说这地方是他们的
Then they started hunting us down.
然后开始追杀我们
This time, we're the ones doing the hunting.
这一次，该我们追杀他们
You've got a lot to say about killing.
说到杀人，你可真是滔滔不绝
Even more words than arrows.
说出的字比做成的箭还多
Back in those villages, I killed just as many of them as you did.
在那些村子里，我杀的人跟你一样多
More, I reckon.
不，估计比你多
Yes, but none of those were your crow lover.
是啊，但没一个是你的乌鸦情人
I probably killed him already.
我说不定已经把他给杀了
So you've said.
你这句话我可记住了
And if not,
要是他没死
the only thing left of him is gonna be his fun bits hanging around my neck.
我就把他那话儿割下来挂在脖子上
More words.
话更多了
Know what I think you do when you see him?
知道我觉得你见到他会做什么吗？
Serve him up a nice juicy slice of ginger minge.
用你那精美多汁的逼去伺候他
You been thinking about that ginger minge?
你是不是一直惦记着逼？
Wondering what it tastes like?
想知道它是什么味道吗？
Maybe I have.
我可能尝过哦
Jon Snow is mine.
琼恩·雪诺是我的
Anyone else tries to kill him,
谁要是敢杀他
I'll have an arrow for them.
我就射他一箭
And not one of your bald friends is fast enough to stop me.
你们这些光头谁也快不过我，别想阻止我
And what is it that couldn't wait until morning, Tarly?
塔利，什么事情这么重要不能等到明早再做？
Maester Aemon.
伊蒙学士
- How did you know-- - That it was you?
- 你怎么知道是我？
- 是你？
Who else but Samwell Tarly
除了山姆威尔·塔利…
would be wasting candles
还有谁浪费蜡烛…
to read in the middle of the night?
在深夜里读书？
- Let me help you. - Oh, no need.
- 我来帮你
- 不用了
I know my way around this library
我很了解图书馆这一片
better than any other place in Castle Black.
比对黑城堡其他地方要了解的多
Thousands of books
这里有成千上万的书
and no eyes to read them.
却没人来读
Old age is a wonderful source of ironies
老来阅遍无尽讽刺
if nothing else.
没别的
But you didn't answer my question.
但是你还没回答我的问题
What are you reading?
你在读什么？
Maester Faull.
缶尔学士
Ah, the wildlings.
哦，是那些野人
I can assure you that the closest Maester Faull
我很确信
ever got to a wildling was this very library.
缶尔学士距离野人最近的地方就是这个图书馆了
But what he says about what they do,
但是他说的有关野人做过的事情
it's all true.
都是真的
It's exactly what the survivors of their raids report.
存活下来的人都是这么报告的
Yes, imagine the stories wildlings tell about us.
是啊，想想那些我们讲过的野人故事
Love is the death of duty.
爱情，是职责的坟墓
I told that to your friend Jon Snow once.
我跟你的朋友琼恩·雪诺说过一次
He didn't listen and neither did you.
他听不进去，你也听不进去
Which is why you've abandoned your watch atop the Wall
这就是为什么你不在那长城上守着
to come here and read about the terrible things
却到这儿来读这些的…
that may have happened to the girl you love.
你爱的女孩的可怕遭遇
I don't love her.
我不爱她
- Yes, you do. - No.
- 不，你爱她
- 不是的
Yes, you do.
你爱她
Heard it in your voice when you first brought her to me.
你第一次带她见我时，我就听出来了
I remember how it sounds.
我还记得恋爱的语气
I was in love once.
我也曾恋爱过
You were?
你恋爱过？
You can imagine all manner of horrors
你能想像出那女人和孩子
befalling that poor girl and her child.
可能会经历的各种可怕遭遇
Is it so difficult to imagine
却很难想象
that an old person was once,
一个老人曾经
more or less, like you?
也会像你这样？
I'm sorry, Maester.
抱歉，学士
I didn't mean it like that.
我不是那个意思
Do you know who I was before I came here?
你知道我来这里之前是什么身份吗？
What I could have been if I'd only said the word?
你知道当初只要我开口，就会获得什么地位吗？
Of course you do.
你肯定知道
I met many girls when I was Aemon Targaryen.
当我还是伊蒙·坦格利安的时候，见识过很多女人
A future king always does.
储君都是如此
Some of them were quite forward
一些女人很主动
in their attempts to win my affections.
想博得我的垂青
One of them succeeded.
其中一人成功了
I was very young.
我当时很年轻
Who was she?
她是谁？
Ah.
啊
I could tell you everything about her.
我可以告诉你她的一切
Who she was,
她是谁
how we met,
我们如何相遇
the color of her eyes,
她眼睛的颜色
and the shape of her nose.
鼻子的形状
I can see her
我能看见她…
right in front of me.
就在我面前
She's more real than you are.
对我来说她比你还要真实
We could spend all night trading tales of lost loves.
我们可以整晚不睡，互相讲述爱情故事
Nothing makes the past a sweeter place to visit
死亡临近最容易让人…
than the prospect of imminent death.
沉醉于怀旧
Go to bed, Tarly.
去睡觉吧，塔利
Sorry, I can't open the gate for anybody. Orders.
抱歉，我不能给任何人开门，这是命令
You don't understand. They killed everyone.
你不懂，他们杀了所有人
Everyone but me and my baby.
除了我和孩子之外的所有人
They're out there. I saw them on my way here.
他们来了，我在来这的路上看见他们了
They may have seen me. They may have followed me. Please.
他们可能发现我了，他们可能在跟踪我，求你了
I'm sorry, I can't.
抱歉，我不能开门
If they find us out here, you don't know...
要是他们发现我们在这，你不知道…
Pyp! Open the gate.
派普尔！开门
- I can't. - Sam, is that you?
- 我不能开
- 山姆，是你吗？
Yes.
是我
Thorne gave me strict orders to not open the gate.
上头严令我不许开门
Oh, Pyp, open the fucking gate!
派普尔，你他妈快给我开门！
I never heard you curse before.
我从来没听你骂过人
Yes, well, best get used to it.
那你最好快适应
Are you all right?
你没事吧？
Shh, you're all right.
嘘，你没事了
Of course you are, my brave little fella.
你肯定会没事的，勇敢的小家伙
- It was horrible. - I'm so, so sorry.
- 太可怕了
- 我非常非常抱歉
I didn't know until I got back.
直到回来我才知道
Don't let them send me away, Sam.
不要让他们赶我走，山姆
- Never. - I know there's no women allowed.
- 绝不会
- 我知道这里不许有女人
Anyone who tries to throw you out will be having words with me.
谁要赶你走得先过我这关
From now on, wherever you go,
从现在起，不管你去哪
I go, too.
我都跟你一起
Get ready!
备战！
- Man the gate! - Ready yourselves!
- 守住大门！
- 准备应战！
Make haste!
快！
- Prepare! - Up on the Wall!
- 快准备！
- 上长城！
Quickly! Up! Up!
赶快！
快上去！上去！
How many? How many are there?
多少？有多少敌人？
Beyond the trees!
在树那边！
It's time.
是时候了
Light them up! Light them all!
点着！全点着！
Move!
快走！
Pick up the pace!
快跟上！
Come on, come on.
快点，快点
Here we go, boys, there's one.
准备好，一个
Let's go. There's two.
起！两个
Let's get the next load.
去拿下一发炮弹
That's the last of the oil, Ser Alliser.
那些是最后的油了，艾里沙爵士
100,000 you say?
你说有十万人？
Yes, Ser.
是，爵士
You can say it if you like.
随便你说吧
We should have sealed the tunnel while we had the chance,
我们应该把隧道封上
like you suggested.
听你的提议
It was a difficult decision either way, Ser.
本来就是两难的选择，爵士
Do you know what leadership means, Lord Snow?
你知道当领导意味着什么吗，雪诺大人？
It means that the person in charge gets second-guessed
意味着每个长了嘴的混蛋
by every clever little twat with a mouth.
都可以在事后质疑你
But if he starts second-guessing himself,
但如果领导本人也在事后质疑自己
that's the end--
那就完了
for him, for the clever little twats,
他自己，长嘴的混蛋
for everyone.
所有人，都完了
This is not the end. Not for us.
现在还没完，我们还没完
Not if you lot do your duty
只要你们坚守岗位
for however long it takes to beat them back.
直到把敌人击退
And then you get to go on hating me
然后你才能接着恨我
and I get to go on wishing
我也能接着希望
your wildling whore had finished the job.
你的野人婊子当初下手再准点
You'll be safe down here.
这里很安全
I'll check on you as soon as I can.
只要有机会我就来看你
You're leaving me again?
你又要离开我？
I'm not leaving you.
我没要离开你
You're going up there and we're staying down here. That's leaving.
你要上去，而我们留在这下面，这就叫离开
You said from now on we'd stay together.
你说过从现在起我们要在一起
I didn't mean in the same room.
我又不是指在同一房间
What are you going to do out there?
你出去要干什么？
- Help my brothers. - How?
- 帮我的兄弟
- 怎么帮？
You're going to fight the free folk when they come?
自由民来的时候去跟他们打吗？
They'll kill you. In Mole's Town, they killed everyone.
他们会杀了你，他们杀了鼹鼠村所有的人
I can't just hide here with you while they're fighting out there.
他们正在外面作战，我不能跟你躲在这里
Why not? You won't matter up there.
为什么？你出去也没什么用
You will down here.
你在这里有用
I am a man of the Night's Watch, Gilly.
我是守夜人的一员，吉莉
I made a promise to defend the Wall
我发誓会守卫长城
and I have to keep it
我必须遵守誓言
because that's what men do.
这才是男人
Promise me you won't die.
向我保证你不会死
I promise you I won't die.
我向你保证，我不会死
There's a lot more wildlings on the other side of the Wall than this side.
长城那边野人比这边还多
We've got loads of weapons and things.
我们还有这么多武器之类的
It's the perfect place for us to be.
这里最适合我们了
I've never thrown a spear before.
我从没掷过长矛
I've never held a sword with a proper edge.
我从没拿过开好刃的剑
This is no place for me to be.
这里一点也不适合我
You're not afraid?
你不害怕？
Of course I'm afraid.
当然害怕
There's a band of wildlings coming to kill us.
一群野人要来杀我们
If you're afraid of a band of wildlings,
如果一群野人你就怕了
how in seven hells did you manage to kill a white walker?
那你怎么能杀异鬼？
I didn't know I was going to kill it.
我不知道我能杀了它
But I had to do something. I didn't have any choice.
但我必须反击，别无选择
It was going to kill Gilly and take the baby.
它要杀死吉莉抢走孩子
If someone had asked me my name right then,
如果当时有人问我叫什么
I wouldn't have known.
我肯定答不出来
I wasn't Samwell Tarly anymore.
我不再是山姆威尔·塔利
I wasn't a steward in the Night's Watch
不再是守夜人的事务官
or son of Randyll Tarly or any of that.
也不再是蓝道·塔利的儿子
I was nothing at all.
我一无所有
And when you're nothing at all,
当你一无所有
there's no more reason to be afraid.
就没有理由害怕了
But you're afraid now?
但你现在害怕吧？
Yes, well...
是啊…
I'm not nothing anymore.
我不再一无所有
Most of their men are up top.
他们的人大多在上面
Didn't count more than 20 down here.
下面不超过20人
Leftovers.
剩下的
They got a big fat one and a little bony one manning the front.
前面有一个胖子和一个瘦子守着
How high are the walls?
城墙有多高？
Well, we'll be up and over before they know what's happened.
在他们发觉前就能上去
Let's kill some crows!
我们去杀乌鸦吧！
Come on!
上！
Come on, brothers!
上，兄弟们！
Archers nock.
弓箭手上箭
Everyone else hold.
其他人待命
Grenn, no!
葛兰，别！
I said nock and hold, you cunts!
我说上箭待命，蠢货！
- Does nock mean draw? - No, Ser!
- 上箭是拉弦的意思吗？
- 不是，爵士！
- Does fucking hold mean fucking drop? - No, Ser!
- 待命是松手的意思吗？
- 不是，爵士！
- You all plan to die here tonight? - No, Ser!
- 今晚你们想在这里送命？
- 不想，爵士！
That's very good to hear. Draw!
很好，拉弦
No, down below!
不，下面！
Draw! Light them up.
拉弦，烧死他们
Come on, get up!
快点，起来！
They're attacking the southern gate!
他们在攻南门！
- Now? - Now.
- 现在?
- 是
I'm going down there. Brother Slynt, you have the Wall.
我要下去，史林特兄弟，你守着长城
What?
什么？
What are you fucking waiting for? Loose!
你他妈还在等什么，放箭！
You heard the man. Loose!
听到了吧，放箭！
You, over there.
你，那边
- Did you get one? - No.
- 你有射中吗？
- 没有
Ah, shit, Pyp! Shit.
该死，派普！该死
- Sam. - Yeah?
- 山姆
- 啊？
I think we're gonna die.
我觉得我们死定了
If you keep missing, we will.
你再射不中就真死定了
Come on! Come on!
快！快！
Brothers!
兄弟们！
100 generations have defended this castle.
上百代人守卫了这个城堡
She's never fallen before.
她从未陷落
She will not fall tonight.
今晚也不会
Those are Thenns at our walls.
爬我们城墙的是瑟恩人
They eat the flesh of the men they kill.
他们吃所杀之人的肉
Do you want to fill the belly of a Thenn tonight?
今晚你们想填饱瑟恩人的肚子吗？
No!
不想！
Tonight we fight.
今晚我们要战斗
And when the sun rises, I promise you,
等到天亮，我保证
Castle Black will stand!
黑城堡会屹立不倒！
The Night's Watch will stand.
守夜人会屹立不倒
With me now! Now with me!
跟我上！跟我上！
No discipline. No training.
没有纪律，未经训练
Gang of thieves, that's all this is.
只是一帮小偷
I commanded the City Watch of King's Landing.
我指挥过君临都城守备队
Those men obeyed orders.
他们服从命令
We can't just let them attack the gate!
我们不能任由他们攻门！
The bars of those gates are four inches of cold-rolled steel.
那些城门的门闩是四英寸的冰冷钢条
Those are giants riding mammoths down there!
他们是骑着猛犸的巨人！
Do you think your cold-rolled steel is gonna stop them?
你觉得你的冰冷钢条能阻止他们？
No such thing as giants.
哪有巨人
A story for the children.
童话而已
Brother Slynt.
史林特兄弟
We just got word that Ser Alliser needs you below.
我们收到话说艾里沙爵士在下面需要你
You're the most experienced man he's got, Ser, and he needs you.
你是他身边经验最丰富的人，爵士，他需要你
Needed below?
下面需要我？
Yes. Yes.
是，是
Archers, nock your arrows!
弓箭手，上箭！
Nock arrows!
上箭！
Draw!
拉弦！
Loose!
放箭！
They won't summit before dawn.
他们天亮前到不了
How do you know that?
你怎么知道？
Because I've made that climb.
因为我爬过
I think they're in a bigger hurry than you were.
我觉得他们比你快多了
Hold the bridge!
拉住桥！
Hold, wait for it!
拉住，等等！
Come on with the rocks!
石头快点！
Nock!
上箭！
Draw!
拉弦！
Loose!
放箭！
Down!
蹲下！
No! No!
不！不！
To the gate. Come on, let's move.
去门那里，快点，我们走
It's gonna open.
它会开的
I got one right through the heart. He's dead.
我射中一个人的心脏，他死了
- Oh, is it over? - No.
- 结束了？
- 没有
Well, then...
那么…
You're all right. You're all right.
你会没事的
I'll get help.
我去找人帮忙
Shh. Shh.
嘘，嘘
Maester Aemon is coming.
伊蒙学士来了
He's gonna make it all right.
他会救你的
Shh. Shh.
嘘，嘘
- Now. - Now!
- 放
- 放！
The outer gate won't hold.
外门抵不住了
Take five men, hold the inner gate.
带五个人，守住内门
Aye.
是
Hold the gate.
守住门
If they make it through...
一旦他们突破…
They won't.
他们休想
Come on, Hill. And you, Cooper.
过来，希山，还有你，库珀
You three, on me.
你们三个，跟我来
Come on, you lazy bastards.
快点，懒猪
Oil.
倒油
Oil on the ramp!
油上坡道！
Protect the gate!
守住门！
Get him inside.
带他进去
Hold the fucking gate!
他妈的守住门！
Hold it!
守住！
We need more men down here.
这里需要更多人手
- We have to hold the gate. - But we need men here.
- 我们必须守住门
- 但这里需要人手
Tell Jon. He's in command.
跟琼恩说，他在指挥
Let's go.
我们走
Get me to the top! You hear me?!
带我上去！听到没？！
Your name's Olly, right?
你是奥利吧？
Listen to me, Olly. Get me to the top.
听我说，奥利，让我上去
And when we give the signal, bring us back down.
等我们给信号，再放我们下来
You hear me?
听到没？
Find a weapon, Olly. Fight them.
找件武器，奥利，跟他们打
Clear the way! Let's go!
快让开！我们走！
- Out of the way! - Get out of here!
- 快让开！
- 离开那里！
Cut the rope!
砍断绳子！
Wait! No!
等等！不！
- We need more archers. - Here I am.
- 我们需要弓箭手
- 我来了
- Come on. - Quickly.
- 快点
What are you doing up here?
你来这里干嘛？
The wildlings are over the walls.
野人已经翻过城墙
Ser Alliser's fallen.
艾里沙爵士已倒下了
The castle won't stand much longer.
城堡坚持不了多久
Edd, you have the Wall.
艾迪，长城交给你
If they try the mammoths again, drop fire on them.
如果他们再用猛犸，就投火
If the climbers get too high, drop the scythe on them.
攀爬的人爬高了，就放大镰刀
Come, brothers. Now fight with me!
来吧，弟兄们，跟我一起！
Might as well enjoy our last night, right, boys?
最后一晚干脆好好享受，孩子们？
Light the fuckers up!
烧死这帮混蛋！
Nock! Draw!
点火！拉弓！
Loose!
放箭！
How are we gonna stop that?
我们怎么阻止他？
Shot 20 arrows in him already.
射他20箭
You heard Jon. We hold the gate.
琼恩说了，守住大门
Jon Snow's not Lord Commander.
琼恩·雪诺不是指挥官
We hold the gate!
守住大门！
Mother, save me. Father, save me.
圣母，拯救我
天父，拯救我
The gods aren't down here.
神不在这里
It's the six of us. You hear me?
只有我们6个，你听到没？
Night gathers and now my watch begins.
长夜将至，我从今开始守望…
It shall not end until my death.
至死方休
I shall take no wife, hold no lands,
我将不娶妻，不封地…
father no children.
不生子
I shall wear no crown and win no glory.
我将不戴宝冠，不争荣宠
I shall live and die at my post.
我将尽忠职守，生死于斯
I am the sword in the darkness.
我是黑暗中的利剑
I am the watcher on the walls.
长城上的守卫
I am the shield that guards the realms of men.
守护王国的坚盾
I pledge my life and honor to the Night's Watch
我将生命与荣耀献给守夜人…
for this night and all the nights to come!
今夜如此，夜夜皆然！
I don't want you out there.
我不希望你出去
You can't protect me forever.
你不能永远保护我
There won't be anywhere to hide if the castle falls.
城堡陷落，也无处躲藏了
I need him more than I need you.
我需要他多过需要你
We need you, boy.
我们需要你，小子
Ha!
Jon Snow.
琼恩·雪诺
Hush. Don't talk.
嘘，别说话
Do you remember the cave?
还记得山洞吗？
We should have stayed in the cave.
我们应该待在洞里
We'll go back there.
我们会回去的
You know nothing, Jon Snow.
你什么都不知道，琼恩·雪诺
Drop the scythe, boys!
放镰刀，兄弟们！
- Hoist her up. - Hoist her up!
- 拖上来
- 拖上来！
They've had enough for one night.
今晚够他们受的了
Don't cheer too loud.
别高兴太早了
They still outnumber us 1,000 to one.
他们仍然千倍于我们
Tormund.
托蒙德
It's over.
结束了
Let it end.
放弃吧
This is how a man ends.
男人应该这样结束
Put him in chains.
把他锁起来
We'll question him later.
以后再审问他
from the top of the Wall, boy!
I should have thrown you
我该把你从城墙上推下去的，小子！
Aye.
是啊
You should have.
应该推
Whoa, it's me. It's me.
是我，是我
I promised you, didn't I?
我答应你的，对吗？
We held them off.
我们顶住了
For one night.
只一晚
This is a great victory.
这是场大胜
A great victory?
大胜？
Mance was testing our defenses.
曼斯只是在测试我们的防守
He almost made it through.
他差点就攻了进来
And he has more giants. He has more mammoths.
他还有很多巨人，很多猛犸
He has 1,000 times as many men.
还有千倍于此的人
They'll hit us again tonight.
他们今晚会再进攻
Maybe we can hold them off for a day or two,
也许我们能顶住一两天
but we'll never beat them.
但不可能打败他们
Where are we going?
我们要去哪？
Going to find Mance.
去找曼斯
To fi--- you can't do that.
去找…你不能去
No one gave you any orders.
没人给你命令
Who's left to give orders?
还有人下命令吗？
The wildling army's only an army because of Mance.
野人因曼斯而成为军队
He united 100 warring tribes.
他联合了100个杀伐的部落
Without Mance, they lose their leader.
没有曼斯，就一盘散沙
They lose their purpose. They go back to fighting each other.
没有目标，他们又会互相争斗
Scatter back to their homes.
卸甲归田
Without Mance?
没有曼斯？
You're going to kill him?
你要去杀了他？
I'm gonna try.
我要试试
They'll never let you within 100 yards of him.
他们不会让你靠近他
And even if they did, even if you managed to kill him--
就算靠近了，就算你杀了他…
They'll kill me? If I don't go, they'll kill me anyway.
他们会杀了我？我不去，左右是死
They'll kill the rest of us, too.
他们会杀光我们
They won't just kill you.
他们不会杀你
They'll boil you. They'll flay you.
他们会煮了你，剥皮
They'll make it last days.
折磨你好久
You're right. It's a bad plan.
你说得对，这是下策
What's your plan?
你有办法吗？
They held the gate.
他们守住了大门
Get some brothers down here to help you.
找些兄弟下来帮你
We need to burn the bodies.
得把尸体烧了
Raise the outer gate.
升起外门
Then lower it again as soon as I'm out.
我一出去就落闸
What are you doing?
你干什么？
I promised Mormont I'd never lose it again.
我答应过莫尔蒙不再弄丢了
In case I don't come back.
以防万一我回不来
Jon.
琼恩
Come back.
一定回来
-=TLF字幕组=-
谢谢观赏
TLF中文字幕站 http://sub.eastgame.org/
微博地址：http://weibo.com/tlfsubs
豆瓣小站：http://site.douban.com/127446/